export const chapter = "Chapter - 11: The Colonial Rule and Changes in Arts ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the earliest example of art mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Writing",
        optionB: "Painting",
        optionC: "Music",
        correctAnswer: "b) Painting",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which invention made it easier to communicate writing to a large number of people?",
        optionA: "Printing press",
        optionB: "Camera",
        optionC: "Mobile phone",
        correctAnswer: "a) Printing press",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the context of art, what has the invention of the computer contributed to?",
        optionA: "Photography",
        optionB: "Literature",
        optionC: "New patterns and pictures",
        correctAnswer: "c) New patterns and pictures",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How has social media impacted the spread of art in modern times?",
        optionA: "Hindered the reach of art to a larger audience",
        optionB: "Helped spread art to a larger number of people",
        optionC: "Had no impact on the arts",
        correctAnswer: "b) Helped spread art to a larger number of people",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the negative aspect of the synthesis of different forms of art, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Enhanced creativity",
        optionB: "Preservation of traditional art forms",
        optionC: "Threat to unique art forms",
        correctAnswer: "c) Threat to unique art forms",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What historical event motivated literature to express nationalism in different ways and forms?",
        optionA: "The invention of the printing press",
        optionB: "The advent of colonial rule in India",
        optionC: "The introduction of modern communication means",
        correctAnswer: "b) The advent of colonial rule in India",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which writer is mentioned as an important figure in Hindi and Urdu literature?",
        optionA: "Rabindranath Tagore",
        optionB: "Kishan Chandra",
        optionC: "Munshi Premchand",
        correctAnswer: "c) Munshi Premchand",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What form of art is famous for its rich style in the medieval period?",
        optionA: "Poetry",
        optionB: "Painting",
        optionC: "Drama",
        correctAnswer: "b) Painting",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which building in Delhi is mentioned in the text as a significant example of architecture from the colonial period?",
        optionA: "India Gate",
        optionB: "Victoria Memorial",
        optionC: "Lotus Temple",
        correctAnswer: "a) India Gate",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the modern period, what materials were tried for painting in India?",
        optionA: "Wood and earth",
        optionB: "Canvas, paper, watercolor, and oil color",
        optionC: "Stone and clay",
        correctAnswer: "b) Canvas, paper, watercolor, and oil color",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Art finds expression in different ways, such as in writing, painting, music, and sculpture. Rock painting is the ____________ example of art.",
        optionA: "earliest",
        optionB: "most recent",
        optionC: "abstract",
        correctAnswer: "earliest",
      },
      {
        question:
          "With time, new tools came into existence which gave expression to art. When paper was invented, it became easier to ____________ and draw.",
        optionA: "dance",
        optionB: "sing",
        optionC: "write",
        correctAnswer: "write",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The invention of the computer has given wings to arts in a big way. New patterns of paintings and pictures have taken a ____________ stage.",
        optionA: "backstage",
        optionB: "front-row",
        optionC: "center",
        correctAnswer: "center",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The social media has helped to spread the art works to a larger number of people in ____________ time.",
        optionA: "no",
        optionB: "a short",
        optionC: "a long",
        correctAnswer: "a short",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Breaking Away of Barriers in Art: In the past, it was not possible to transmit a piece of art to other cultures and regions easily, so the intercultural impact remained ____________.",
        optionA: "limited",
        optionB: "significant",
        optionC: "overwhelming",
        correctAnswer: "limited",
      },
      {
        question:
          "This synthesis has its negative aspect too. With mingling of different forms of arts, some people have started to feel that the existence of their unique art forms is being ____________.",
        optionA: "enhanced",
        optionB: "threatened",
        optionC: "celebrated",
        correctAnswer: "threatened",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Literature in the modern period started to express nationalism in different ways and forms. Thus, stories and poetry were composed to motivate people to fight the ____________ rule.",
        optionA: "foreign",
        optionB: "local",
        optionC: "traditional",
        correctAnswer: "foreign",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Most of the Indian writers wrote in ____________ languages, and not in English or French.",
        optionA: "European",
        optionB: "native",
        optionC: "ancient",
        correctAnswer: "native",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the modern period, painting came to be influenced by current topics, such as social reforms, ____________, etc.",
        optionA: "mythology",
        optionB: "politics",
        optionC: "religion",
        correctAnswer: "politics",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Different architectural styles such as Hindu, Persian, Mughal, and western made their presence felt in different buildings and monuments in the ____________ period.",
        optionA: "ancient",
        optionB: "medieval",
        optionC: "colonial",
        correctAnswer: "colonial",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Art is primarily expressed through various mediums such as writing, painting, music, and sculpture.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The earliest example of art mentioned in the text is digital art created on computers.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The printing press made it easier to communicate writing and drawings to a large number of people.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The advent of the camera improved its features over time, resulting in better-quality photographs.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The social media has not played a role in spreading art works to a larger number of people.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The invention of the computer had no significant impact on the field of arts.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Literature during the modern period primarily focused on religious and mythological subjects.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Literature started to express nationalism in different ways and forms after the 1857 First War of Independence.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The colonial period had no influence on the styles and subjects of literature in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Painting in the modern period continued to be influenced by bright colors and traditional styles.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
